RITU PANDE

Apartment 303 24456 Conifer Farmington Hills, MI, 48335 United States

Profile

Technology principal, specializing in applied cryptography, public key infrastructure and security architecture for connected embedded devices. Experience in technically building and mentoring large teams to take a product/service from conceptualization/pre-sales to production.

Mobile: +1-248-756-9513

I am also an independent researcher, collaborating with experts in academia. My research interests include:

- Graph Neural Networks
- Group Convolutions
- Self-Organizing Systems

For more information please refer <u>ritupande.github.io</u>

Research Experience:

- Publications
 - Hierarchical Neural Cellular Automata, R Pande, D Grattarola Artificial Life Conference (ALife 2023) | Paper, Code, Talk
- Projects
 - Adaptive Traffic Signal Control using Deep Reinforcement Learning. Code
- Skills
 - Tensor Flow, Numpy, Python, Object Oriented Programming
 - Self-organizing systems, Neural Cellular Automata, Deep Learning, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Graph Neural Networks
- Certifications.
 - Natural Language Processing Specialization
 - AI for Medicine
 - Mathematics for Machine Learning
 - Deep Learning Specialization
 - Reinforcement Learning Specialization

Professional Experience:

Employment

Company	Designation	Duration
General Motors	Software Architect, Technology Lead	Oct 2021 – Till date
Capgemini Group/ Altran Group/ Aricent Technologies/ Hughes Software Systems	 Director Technology Principal Systems Engineer Senior Technical Lead Technical Lead Senior Software Engineer 	July 2004 - Oct 2021
Wipro Technologies	Software Engineer	Oct 2002-July 2004
Innodata Information Technologies	System Engineer	Aug 2001 - Sept-2002

Recent Projects

- General Motors connected car infotainment (2014- Till Date).

Lead Security Architect responsible for:

- Authoring PKI specification for all connected ECUs capturing procurement, renewal and revocation strategy of device end-entity certificates.
- o Authoring Secured Onboard Communication (SecOC) specification for infotainment ECU.
- Authoring specification for flexible key provisioning for infotainment ECU at plant and assembly.
- Designing strategy for integration of ECU key store with trusted applications in Qualcomm Trusted Execution Environment.
- Designing ECU trusted certificate store strategy.
- Mentoring and training implementation teams on security and applied cryptography fundamentals.
- Leading end-to-end integration of the security features between connected infotainment ECU and the back-end servers.
- o Threat modelling for attack vectors on connected ECUs.

Lead Power and State Management Architect, responsible for: (2014- Till Date)

- Authoring specification for power and state management for infotainment ECU
- Technically leading implementation teams within General Motors and Tier-I suppliers to implement the power and state management functionality across SoC and Vehicle Interface Processor in infotainment ECU.
- o Spearhead triaging and execution
- Nokia Siemens Network(NSN) Femto Access Point (FAP) (2013- 2014)

Project Technical lead for the design and execution of security solution in FAP device.

- Designing the Trusted Execution Environment strategy in FAP using ARM Trustzone architecture.
- Technically leading the porting and integration of Aricent developed LTE stacks on SoC vendor's (Broadcom) BSP.
- Designing and leading execution of integration and optimization strategy of ciphering at LTE air interface with SoC provided HW accelerators.
- Leading the integration of encryption in the IPSec layer of Linux kernel with SoC provided HW accelerators.
- Technically leading the design and execution of integration of Strongswan Internet Key Exchange version 2 (IKEv2) stack on Linux operating system with FAP fast path.
- Designing and leading execution of secure boot strategy for FAP
- Leading the execution of strategy for secure over-the-air download and subsequent flashing of firmware.
- Designing the IP filter rules for implementing NATing in the FAP device.
- Nokia Siemens Network (NSN) Flexi-Edge Base Transceiver Station (BTS) (2009-2013)

Feature Lead for design and execution of security and transport solutions for the base station

- Technically leading the design and execution of integration of Strongswan Internet Key Exchange version 2 (IKEv2) stack on QNX operating system with fast path executed in network processor.
- Technically leading the architecture, design and execution of CLM strategy for procurement, renewal and revocation of device end-entity certificates in the BTS

Skills

Security architecture for embedded devices, Applied Cryptography, Public Key Infrastructure,

Platform Security, Transport Layer Security, Android Security, Trusted Execution Environment, Secure Programming, Secured Onboard Communication.

- Automotive Network Architecture, Vehicle Power Management, IP Transport, L2/L3 Switching
- Creating technical proposals detailing solutions to customer requirements and effectively presenting them.
- Programming Languages: C, object-oriented Python
- Tools: Jira, Github, Enterprise Architect
- Operation Systems: Linux, QNX
- Standards: X.509, IKEv2, IPsec, TLSv2, SHE, TrustZone
- Excellent verbal and oral communication skills

Leadership Experience:

- Experience in leading technical task force across multiple tier-1 suppliers and OEM teams to bring product features to fruition from their concept inception to deployment.
- Extensive experience in technically building and mentoring large teams (largest team size being 45) in the area of IP transport, security and layer 2 switching and routing strategies.
- Deft at providing technical leadership across parallel projects, resolving interface issues across multiple subsystems.

Teaching Experience:

- Aricent Technologies: Organizational trainer for 'Debugging Skills'.
- General Motors: Organizational trainer for 'Security and Applied Cryptography Fundamentals'.

Educational Qualifications:

Bachelor of Information Tech. (1997-2001) Indraprastha College, Delhi University, India.

Awards and Achievements:

- 1 Certificate of Merit in National Mathematics Olympiad competition, 1995
- 2 Individual Employee Excellence award, Altran Group, 2008

Extra-Curricular Achievements:

- 1. 1st Degree Black Belt holder in ITF Tae-kwon-do
- 2. 1 Gold and 1 Silver in South Asian Tae-kwon-do Championships (ITF), Dec 2008
- 3 2 Gold and 1 Silver in National Tae-kwon-do Championships, Dec 2006
- 4 Completed Airtel Delhi Half Marathon '09 and '10

I hereby agree that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Ritu Pande